# Gloria Christiana Maria

Jl. Cipinang Elok Pertama No.9, DKI Jakarta, Jakarta Timur developeronboards@gmail.com +62 821-2202-1918

### Summary

Enthusiastic and driven design engineer with diverse experience across different project life cycle. Applied research-based principles to drive the design of products that fully support end-user needs while also achieving the business vision. Led user research and interface design processes creating personas, visualizations, story boards, task flows, wireframes, high-fidelity mockups, and prototypes. Continuously measured and optimized the user experience through a combination of quantitative and qualitative research methods.

### **Portfolio**

Please check this website: <a href="https://gloriachm.vercel.app/">https://gloriachm.vercel.app/</a>

### **Experience**

## Lead UI/UX Engineer

Quadrant by Appen • Jakarta

11/2020 - Present

- Injected Lean UX paradigms into Agile development processes significantly improving the scrum team's velocity and overall collaboration while placing the user at the core of the lifecycle.
- Building design system for across departments both UX and Engineering
- Pioneered the use of remote user testing tools to gather feedback early and often while also increasing velocity and reducing associated research costs.
- Created the first Product Advisory Board / Customer Panel which provided the ability to rapidly experiment and refine design ideas throughout the product lifecycle.
- Assimilated internal data, performed task analysis, comparative benchmarking using SUS, and formative discovery testing to iterate and improve usability of products that were being redesigned.
- Led UX efforts on innovation business intelligence systems, researching and designing new campaign, data visualizations, and end-user interactions related to large data sets.
- Spearheaded UX on a new innovation web-product offering, coordinating all UX related efforts and leading all research and design.
- UX and Front-End OKRs yearly and quarterly planning and SOP.
- Assisted the company in hiring new candidates for designer positions.

## Lead UI/UX Engineer

PT Bank Mandiri, Tbk • Jakarta

12/2019 - 11/2020

- Develop and document end-product specifications that support downstream development and implementation work e.g. use cases, test scenarios, design artifacts
- Collaborate with our team Work closely with product owner, business analyst, engineering, and customer success throughout product development lifecycle
- · Analyse existing data structures and assist with development of logical and physical data models
- Work closely with the product management team to formulate strategic product direction
- · Work with developers to implement strategies that ensure technical success using PEGA

## **UI/UX Engineer**

Monad Tech • Jakarta 02/2018 - 12/2019

• Work with the entire product team to contribute to high-level direction and ideas for the product.

- Work directly with the Design Leader to define specs and set goals for projects.
- · Work closely with engineers to ensure the build matches visual design and help with front-end development
- Translate ideas (business needs and user goals) into elegant, intuitive, and engaging user experiences Improve current product and help design the next set of features.
- Own end-to-end design deliverables from specifications, process flows, and wireframes to final visual mock-ups.
- Drive the development and communication of design guidelines and patterns, with focus on providing a consistent experience on any platform.
- Provide hands-on design and creative direction for all design needs, across different mediums.

## **UI/UX Engineer**

Transcosmos Indonesia • Jakarta

02/2016 - 01/2018

- Developed design deliverables that elevate, differentiate and function on-brand and on-strategy digital and print marketing collateral.
- Design both for website and mobile application
- · Visionary creator for motion graphics, art for videos, logos and social media posts.
- Responsible for key messaging, including audience promotions and advertising. Create user interface design style for the member/clients portal.
- Assists with communication plans and develop creative briefs and design concepts to meet overall objectives.
- Conceptualization and visualization Creating various layouts for Magazines, Posters, Flyers, Banners, mailers, clothing, and e-cards creations.
- Coordinated with Marketing Department to layout and design all new marketing collateral, while strictly adhering to established brand standards and templates.

## **UI/UX Facilitator (Part-Time)**

Binar Academy • Jakarta

11/2020 - 10/2021

- Support and teach students using e-learning, focus on business, ux design and front-end development (Soft skills and hard skills)
- Planning, creation and implementation of quarter syllabus
- Grading projects completed by students and documentation

## **UI/UX Engineer - Animator**

Freelancer • Jakarta

06/2015 - Present

- Designed for clients Branding, logo, stationary, brochures, business cards, banners, flyers, billboards, commercial ads, newspaper ads, advertising campaigns
- Also delivered booth designs, vehicle graphics and wraps, t-shirt design. web interface graphics, wix, wordpress, retouching, magazines, social media, eblast, drawing.
- Made website/mobile designs and front-end development for client's companies
- 3D animation and video for marketing purpose

### **Education**

## Master of Informatics Technology

Bina Nusantara University • Jakarta 03/2020

• Graduated cum laude - 3.6+ GPA out of 4.0

## **Bachelor of Computer Science**

Bina Nusantara University • Jakarta 08/2018

Graduated —3.4+ GPA out of 4.0

## **Achievement**

- Improved user retention rate by 37% after conceptualizing and validating user onboarding flows through A/B tests.
- Increased the company's revenue by 12% and user NPS rate from 7 to 9 points by redesigning the flow while working closely with designers, engineers, marketing and product managers.
- Helped the company make better branding, principal and consistency with building the Design System for across platforms and departments
- Led the cross-team initiative in a visual design system development and implementation.
- Boosted the user conversion rate by 14% through delivering a more engaging graphical content across all mediums while working alongside the marketing team.
- Running more than 50 campaigns across countries with success percentages 95% (Indonesia, Singapore, Philippine, Malaysia, London, Sydney)
- Building stable Power BI with Data Science for reporting across products
- Increase accessibility 18% pro into blind color people
- Testing outcomes (Direct and remote approach) with result Misclick rates below 50%, Avg duration Below 10 sec. Avg success 90%, Avg bounce below 30%, Total Usability score Above 85
- Success new feature release with NFT gamification
- Increase transaction company crypto value up to 39%

#### Skills

- Highly professional, with the ability to deliver solid work on tight schedules
- · Solid intuition and strong passion for detailed interaction design
- Great design communication skills; able to describe the function and purpose of a design to all team members
- Ability to work in a fast paced work environment with a high sense of urgency and able to adapt to changing priorities
- · Good understanding development cycles from research, design, development, and testing
- Good understanding in Tech languages (HTML, CSS, JS, React, Flutter, Python, Java, Swift, PHP)

### Certificate

UX Designer Certified by Interaction Designer Foundation, UI/UX Engineer Certified by Uxcel, Development Certified by Freecodecamp Org, Motion Graphic Certified by Motion Design School, Swift Beginner Developer by Dicoding Academy, UI/UX Design and Interaction Certified by LinkedIn, Data Science Foundation Certified by LinkedIn, React and ES6 Certified by Wes Bos, Flutter Beginner Developer Certified by BuildWithAngga

### Tool

### DESIGN

- Figma, Adobe XD, Axure RP 9, Sketch
- · Balsamiq, Zeplin, Invision
- · Maze, HotJar

## **PRODUCT**

- · JIRA, Confluence
- Notion
- HubSpot, MailChimp, Google Analytics

### DEVELOPMENT

- VS Code, Git, PEGA
- · WIX, Wordpress

### Language